CHIJIOKE **NWAGWU**

30 Gregory Arueya Street, Kosofe, Lagos · 2348037664940

wyhzest@gmail.com · https://github.com/wisestme . https://www.linkedin.com/in/wisestme/

Twitter: @wisestMe

Skilled and experienced Technical Customer Supporter with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer electronics industry. Versatility with passion for learning and problem solving has led me to becoming a strong information technology professional in Frontend Web Development and Software Engineering with an unparalleled and result oriented work attitude.

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2020 - MAY 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (INTERN), TENECE PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

- Learning core software development concepts using the C# programming language.
- Building Web Applications using the ASP.Net MVC.

OCTOBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

WEB DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR, FOUNDATION FOR MORAL VALUE REORIENTATION (UNPAID INTERNSHIP)

- I provided the foundation with a training guide for Front End Web Development and a blueprint for new courses in the future.
- I trained over 25 absolute beginners within a period of five months, to give them a kick start to their programming journey in Front End Web Development. With a follow up to ensure they maintain a healthy momentum.

APRIL 2018 – JANUARY 2020

SCHOLAR, ANDELA LEARNING COMMUNITY (REMOTE)

I advanced from an absolute beginner to a proficient Front End Web developer, making it to the project phase where I built my first Angular Application on the Pluralsight platform.

AUGUST 2019 – OCTOBER 2019

INTERN, HNG TECH (REMOTE)

I joined the online community where I was able to improve on my Front End Engineering skills where I learned more on how to collaborate remotely and also got the opportunity to provide my team with a mock up UI Design using Figma for one of our HTML, CSS and JavaScript project. In collaborating, I was also able to transform some mock ups into the required code using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

JULY 2019 – AUGUST 2019

ROBOTICS INSTRUCTOR, TANTEETA ROBOTICS

I facilitated two centers of about 20 kids in all and I was able to help them build and program a robot. In the process I got them to understand the basic principles of material design and programming with some necessary skills like critical thinking, algorithmic development, importance of collaboration and teamwork.

MARCH 2019 – APRIL 2019

INTERN, ULTRA MEDIA SOLUTIONS (UNPAID)

I ran daily online promotions of the company's services on major social media and I learned how to make use of Wordpress to create web pages.

MAY 2016 - FEBRUARY 2019

TECHNICAL CUSTOMER SUPPORT SPECIALIST, CONTACT SOLUTIONS LIMITED

Responsible for ensuring Samsung Mobile phone users in West Africa get the right resolution for reported issues.

- I Managed the Samsung Members application for West Africa comprising of about Three Hundred Thousand members ensuring that all question, complaints and error reports are resolved in a timely and satisfactory manner.
 - I constantly engaged Samsung Mobile phone users with the latest tips to ensure they get the
 most out of their devices, giving them value for their money to ensure they remain loyal to our
 brand.
 - I escalate customers' suggestions and other necessary cases to the Samsung Headquarters R&D department for enhancement in future designs.
 - I monitor and conduct weekly training for the Level one customer care agents keep them up to speed with the latest technical information to ensure they are able to support our customers within their scope and then I handle cases beyond their scope.
 - I conduct remote management on customers' phones to ensure that all cases are resolved but cases that require physical attention at our service centres.
 - I monitor the risk level of cases registered at the Samsung authorized services centres all over West Africa and take proactive measures for proper resolution, customer satisfaction and cost cutting.

FEBRUARY 2012 - APRIL 2016

WORKSHOP TECHNICIAN, CELLULAR SERVICE LOGISTICS LIMITED

Responsible for Hardware and Software repairs of Samsung Mobile phones.

- I handled quick diagnoses for possible resolution before customer complaint is registered at the front desk to ensure that the customer fault is reported correctly and to ensure fast repair when possible.
- I handled the repeated repair cases to avoid recurrence of the fault thereby saving the company from incurring the cost and penalty of falling below the acceptable repeat repair ratio.
- I train new technicians.
- I conduct customer education after repair when necessary.
- I escalate production errors (hardware and software) to the Samsung Field Technical support team for West Africa to enable them effect timely correction to the design.

EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2018

NANODEGREE, FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT, UDACITY

OCTOBER 2009

HND ELECTRICAL/ELECTRONICS, AUCHI POLYTECHNIC AUCHI-Lower credits

OCTOBER 2006

OND ELECTRICAL/ELECTRONICS, AUCHI POLYTECHNIC AUCHI-upper credits

AUGUST 2004

SSCE, KOSOFE SENIOR COLLEGE

SKILLS

- C# Programming
- Semantic HTML
- Cascading Style Sheet
- JavaScript
- Responsive Design
- Accessible Design

- ASP.NET MVC
- Unity Game Development
- Good Listener
- Adobe Illustrator
- Bootstrap
- Eager and Fast to Learn

CERTIFICATIONS

- More C# Programming and Unity (University of Colorado)
- Introduction to C# and Unity (University of Colorado)
- Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree (Udacity)
- Google Africa Scholarship Front-End Course (Andela)
- Beginner Software Development Training (HNG Internship)
- Front End Developer (HNG Internship)
- Full-stack Development Track (Udacity)
- Build Your First Web Pages (Open-Classrooms)
- Learn Programming with JavaScript (Open-Classrooms)

BIO

Male Born January 8th, 1987 Abia State